really excited. Uh get chance to add a
uh talented pass rusher in the Keem. Um
guy honestly we we didn't think would
make it to us. Um and uh and just fired
up. He's a you guys read all the reports
on but he's a relentless motor, highly
productive pass rusher, uh physical
player versus the run and uh just a guy
that's his motor just it never never
turns off uh when you put the film on.
and um obviously he was on a you know a
heater all year and played some of his
best ball down the stretch in the
playoffs. So really fired up to get him.
>> Jim, your thoughts on
>> Oh, uh same. I mean it's uh just
thinking of it's not even pairing, it's
tripling, you know, with uh Kmak and
Tulie. That's fire as the young people
would say. Uh
>> super excited. Yeah, it's just uh and uh
a lot of lot of cool things we could
say, but uh we're uh yeah, bolt up.
Let's go. It's uh you know this the the
draft is really I mean kind of that that
that final piece where your you know
your roster comes together and you know
after this weekend you know what the you
know who's going to be you know what
your team is and um
so this is the first piece of putting
that puzzle together and uh super
excited to have a team.
>> Um, how how do you feel like he
compliments Tuli and Khalil? How does it
sort of fit in in terms of play style of
how those guys play?
>> Yeah, I mean all down player, you know,
where we call him three down or four
down players. Uh, you know, that's
that's what he is. Inside pass rush,
outside pass rush. Uh, you know, that
hear the talk about the designated pass
rusher. you know, he's uh but he's also
he can also fit the run uh in the from
the inside in the inside gaps and uh he
can uh you know, build the run wall on
the edge. So that that that that's the
that versatile player. I mean, so much
like uh well, compare him to anybody
because I it's always unfair, but uh
it's just uh yeah, really top player
that like Joe said, we didn't we didn't
think was going to be there, but uh
we're super excited when he was. I'd
just say it's versatility, you know,
like when you get versatile players
along the line of scrimmage.
I'm not a coach, I'm not Chris, you
know, I'm not Dylan and Mike, but you
can get creative with the with that and
uh you line them up a lot of different
spots and and let them get after it.
>> J, do you feel like you can play inside
on early downs or more so in no passing
situation?
>> In the no passing situation, the second
and longs and the third down much like
Tuli does. I mean, Tuli is so effective
when you playing from the edge or or
playing inside.
>> What did he begin to stand out in the
process?
>> Oh, shoot. I mean, in the fall, our
scouts were on him and uh you know, you
just watched his his game game after
game. Like, you know, he you start and
there's the season begins and heck, it
was Notre Dame. you know, those guys
were getting after it and and uh wow,
they got a couple pass rushers at Miami,
you know, and um and then he just
continued it, you know, and uh so I'd
say the process began in in the fall and
uh scouts were on him and he just just
held steady throughout throughout the
year.
>> He's been consistently good, too. I
mean, if you go back to West Virginia
>> Yeah.
>> and you know, all the way to the
national championship game and
two sacks he had there. Um and
he's going to be we think you know like
like Tulie was you know early uh most of
his career I mean the add on special
teams too you know kickoff kickoff
return uh short area quickness is is
great and he's a worker and what I've
noticed about our team these uh these
first four days is not one guy not one
guy is not in a physically really good
position uh right Now, I mean, not one
guy not. Um, and Keem's a worker. He's
going to he's going to come right in and
and fit into uh um you know, our
culture, our team. Good person, good
player, and um got uh got not afraid to
put in the work. I mean, he's he is he
has proven that uh through his through
his college journey and uh it's going to
it's going to fit well. Yeah, we saw
>> we knew before the pick was announced.
We could tell it was defense based off
Chris's reaction on the camera. Was he
somebody who was,
you know, campaigning for Keem
significantly? Like what was what was
that like? Because it looked like he was
he was pretty excited on the big one.
>> Yeah. Uh campaigning. Um
>> coaches liked him a lot.
>> Yeah, coaches like him a lot.
>> Coaches liked him a lot. Clink Clink
Clink came in with a I mean he he was
super uh he was super fired up too. I
mean just uh you know pass rush it's
it's so important.
>> Yeah.
>> Why you smile?
>> Yeah. I think about Clint's line. He's
like pass rush that's best corner you
can take you know like you know just it
just it was just a funny exchange with
Clink. But
>> yeah but but I would say this. I mean
speaking for the coaches because I
watched it go down the whole the whole
process and so did Joe. I mean uh
>> CO wanted take the best player. pick the
best player for the team. Mike McDaniel,
take the best player. And um same with
same with Vic and and all of our
assistants. Uh Chandler Henley, the
tight end coach, was fired up. I mean,
he was studying all the tight ends
throughout the course of the year. I
mean, nobody got the better of a of a
Mezador. I mean, uh we watched that
through the through the scouting
process. I mean, he was he was dominant.
Uh and a lot of really good tight ends
in this in this draft. There was a lot
made about his age being 25 that
obviously didn't deter you guys. Is it
the play on the field that you guys saw
that obviously you guys said no matter
what?
>> Yeah. Yeah. You you know I mean one this
I think we're going to deal with it now
with NIL going forward and certainly the
co we've we've been through it a little
bit. The players have gotten a little
bit older. Uh so yeah this this is an
older rookie class I'd say and uh age is
what it is you know but he's very he's
experienced. I mean, he he got an
education in football at Miami, you
know, and uh and you know, it's paid
off. And uh so you just watch the film
and he's good. He's a great player that
can help us. And uh you know, age, it's
just a number.
>> He's a man. He's polished. He's ready to
roll. And uh very
>> very uh you know, great character,
mature character. Uh you know, just uh
just fits us good. just in the scouting
process, what what are the downsides of
of taking older player from like a like
GM scouting perspective?
>> Yeah, you know, when you take young
players for solar players, it's like you
you look at the long the long term, you
know, like, hey, second contract, third
contract. Well, you know, I mean, got a
guy who's 34 years old out there, 35,
still kicking ass. So, um,
>> playing like he's 22.
>> Yeah. So looks like he's 22. Are you
kidding me? Um
>> it plays like that.
>> Yeah. But uh so yeah, it's it, you know,
younger, you know, he projects out maybe
more, but you know, I guess that's
that's where it would factor in. But um
listen, Hakee is he's older, but he's
not he's not 35. You know,
>> the se the ceiling's already high and
he's already hit, you know. I mean,
>> he's so polished. Maybe it's maybe it's
more, but I mean it's he's got a high
ceiling and he is it's not projecting up
into that up into that ceiling. So, he's
a man. He's ready to roll.
>> What about his personality that stood
out to you guys? Because right away you
said, "I'm ready to come in. I'm ready
to play football. I want to get to the
facility." Like, he just seems so eager
to already be out there.
>> Yeah. you know, just the the sources at
schools and, you know, I got I actually
got a text from someone who was at West
Virginia with him and just talked about
how much of a worker is, how great of a
person he is, focused, you know. So, we
we interviewed him in Indie and uh you
just felt that in the room like he's
just he's a football player and uh
mature, driven, um you know, intelligent
and just wants to work and uh you know,
it's going to fit right in here. How big
were the medicals in his evaluation? Uh
he had left foot, right foot
>> Yeah.
>> issues in 203.
>> Yeah. You know, you had one year of
issues and you know, we are we
thoroughly evaluate um everybody
medically and uh take some guys off our
board and uh but there wasn't a concern
with him medically. I don't know if you
would rank him this way, but if if you
did and if you can remember, where would
he fit in terms of interior pass rushers
in this draft?
>> In interior pass rushers in this draft,
>> if you were evaluating tackles and if
you kick him inside as a pass rusher
from the inside, the damage he did
there, like how would that is that
something that you would slot because
you talked about
>> we don't we yeah, we don't we just say
the ver we offer he offers that
versatility where he can go inside but
very high to answer your question. He is
he is very he's so he's very quick off
the ball. He bends really well. Um uses
his hands well. So he can win inside and
outside. I mean he wins on the edge,
too. He's not, you know, it's just that
type of versatility. Some some guys just
aren't as comfortable going in there and
banging against multiple linemen. They
want to work the edge. He he doesn't
care. He just put tell me where to line
up and tell me, you know, and I'll find
I'll attack the quarterback, you know.
So you love that.
>> So there was an edge that went right
after him. couple picks, right? And then
I think we had two more go. So when
you're stacking the edges,
>> Yeah.
>> how big is versatility? Is that a
tiebreaker or is that a, you know, like
when you're measuring which players you
like?
>> Yeah, I think it factors into the into
the process, but in the end, you know,
if a guy's more of an edge rusher and we
just think he's better at that, the
better player doing what he does and how
he plays and it doesn't, you know, it
doesn't make a guy more higher. You
don't set him higher just because he can
go inside. He's just good at doing both,
you know. So, you know, that's where we
we use it all together to rank him. It's
like a wide receiver that can play
outside and in the slot, you know, a
corner that can play nickel and in the
end is is he a good football player
regardless of where you line him up.
>> Yeah. You you heard the term DPR,
designated pass rusher, you know, uh
this is a designated pass rusher who can
also set the edge and,
>> you know, play play first down, second
down. Um so that's that versatility is
is really valuable. Yeah.
>> And and I tell you where Eli ranks high
to me is just players that want to
practice football and play football and
be good at football.
um you know the uh give me those guys
you know give us give us give us those
kind of competitors you know competitors
welcome here.
>> Um do you think he will use the pool
more than any other player that we have
on the uh on the roster that you have on
the roster right now considering his
background I think what did he want to
do a mile a day is what he was working
on at Miami. He might. There's a good
chance some of the guys get in there
though.
>> You can keep that going.
>> We talked quite a bit about
>> the idea of trading down at your
pre-draft presser.
>> Yeah.
>> Were you close? Did you have offers?
>> Uh, we did not have an offer. We had
calls. We had calls and uh there was
interest. I've been working the phones
for 3 days, 4 days, really a week,
honestly, you know, plus. hell. I was
talking to teams in the combine and the
owners meetings. Um, so we were
definitely open to trading down. There
were some teams that were interested at
certain points in the draft and then it
just dried up. You know, like I I said
last week, uh, it's it always takes two
and they have to have a guy there that
they want to come up for and, uh, just
didn't just didn't materialize. But I've
had a number of teams call me about
already today yesterday about moving up
towards our pick in the second and teams
interested in our third round pick. So I
think there'll be plenty of action uh
opportunities
in the in the next couple rounds as
well.
>> Questions been made about before about
the offensive line. What made you guys
go edge instead of line for example?
>> Best player available.
>> He was top of the board.
>> Yep. I was going to say press conference
without somebody asking about the
offense.
>> There's no doubt.
>> How you feeling about that position?
>> Good. Coach and I were talking before we
went down. I told you guys this is a
good deep draft. It is. It's it the top
of the It was going to be volatile in
the first round. There's, you know, you
know, different players, different
needs, um, different ways of drafting.
But I think once we settle in, there's
going to be players in the second, in
the third, you know, in the fourth. I'm
telling you, there's going to be linemen
there available and uh and so and
there's going to be corners there
available and there's going to be
defensive linemen there available and
inside back like there's it's it's a
good draft like throughout the middle
rounds and uh so I feel good about what
we're going to be able to accomplish the
next two days.
Jim, remember you asked any text
exchange with John about the players
that you guys got?
>> Yeah, I I I uh texted him. I just what a
great uh what a great draft they have is
my uh my first coach
Packers coach Tom Minnik when we were uh
playing for the Ann Arbor Juniors
Packers uh used to say heck of a deal.
And uh so I texted him that uh great
great job and heck of a deal as Tom
Minnik would say. And uh he texted back
uh after we picked a Keem and he said
Hakee was a top 10 player for him. So
I even told Joe that Joe pulled it down.
>> Pulled it down. Yeah.
>> Ready to pull it in. Joe.
>> Yeah.
When did you mention the the thing Clint
said to you about the corner or
something? When did he say that? Like
that was today.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. After we after we picked him like
coach was saying how excited he was, you
know.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's not the first time he said
that. That's that's a that's a
>> because they they compliment each other.
Russ compliments the uh the secondary
makes them have to cover shorter amount
of time and and uh secondary the longer
they're able to cover the the more time
our rushers have to get to the
quarterback. So that those things
that works that works together.
>> What does this mean for for Kyle Canard
and his future?
Kyle's uh when I said not one player has
not come back, uh there's not one player
that's not in a really great place right
now. And uh Kyle's never felt better. Uh
you know, probably since his freshman or
sophomore year, he was telling us um he
had a had a uh spur, you know, in there
in his u that got taken out. And you
pointing at
>> uh I wasn't pointing at a joint. I'm not
a doctor as you know,
>> but as as he was as he was explaining
it, I mean the the analogy that came to
my mind, you know, where you got a stone
in your you know, like your shoe, you
know, it's just makes it hard to to uh
to be at your best. And um so he's in a
great place along with, you know, all
the rest of the guys on the roster. And
uh team's going to be a come out and be
a great fit.